Dr. Julie Imig | Curriculum Vitae

SUMMARY



I am an Astronomical Data Scientist at the Space Telescope Science Institute in Baltimore, Maryland. I received my doctorate degree in Astronomy from New Mexico State University in 2023. My research specializes in uncovering the formation and evolution history of the Milky Way Galaxy using large astronomical surveys.

CURRENT POSITION

2023 - now Astronomical Data Scientist

Space Telescope Science Institute

▶ Working at the Mikulski Archive for Space Telescopes (MAST) archiving astronomical data and sustaining database infrastructure in support of missions including SDSS, TESS, JWST, and HST.

EDUCATION

2017 - 2023 **Doctorate of Philosophy, Astronomy**

New Mexico State University

- ▶ Thesis: A Galactic Self-Portrait: chemical cartography, density modeling, and integrated properties of the Milky Way
- Graduation: May 2023 | GPA: 3.625/4.0

2013 - 2017 Bachelor's Degree, Physics

University of Utah

- ▶ Emphasis: Astrophysics | GPA: 3.731/4.0
- > Thesis: Galactic evolution of phosphorus and sulfur using star clusters

FIRST AUTHOR PUBLICATIONS

Imig et al. 2023 ApJ, in prep. A Galactic Self-Portrait: Density Structure and Integrated Properties of the Milky Way Disk

Pre-print draft: http://astronomy.nmsu.edu/jimig/Imig_MW_density.pdf

Imig et al. 2023 ApJ, 954, 124 A Tale of Two Disks: Mapping the Milky Way with the final data release of APOGEE

https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ace9b8

Imig et al. 2022

SDSS-IV MaStar: Data-driven Parameter Derivation for the MaStar Stellar Library

AJ, 163, 56 https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-3881/ac3ca7

Dr. Julie Imig Publications

FIRST AUTHOR PUBLICATIONS

Imig et al. 2023 ApJ, in prep. ▶ A Galactic Self-Portrait: Density Structure and Integrated Properties of the Milky Way Disk

Pre-print draft: http://astronomy.nmsu.edu/jimig/Imig_MW_density.pdf

Imig et al. 2023 ApJ, 954, 124

▶ A Tale of Two Disks: Mapping the Milky Way with the final data release of APOGEE

https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ace9b8

Imig et al. 2022 AJ, 163, 56

▶ SDSS-IV MaStar: Data-driven Parameter Derivation for the MaStar Stellar Library

https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-3881/ac3ca7

SELECTED CO-AUTHOR PUBLICATIONS

Stone-Martinez et al. 2023 AJ, submitted > Parameter based stellar distances and masses using simple neural nets

Gibson et al. 2023 ApJ, 952 23

▶ The Chemodynamics of the Stellar Populations in M31 from APOGEE Integrated Light Spectroscopy

https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/acd9a9

Hill et al. 2022 MNRAS, 517,3

 \blacktriangleright SDSS-IV MaStar: [α /Fe] for the MaNGA Stellar Library from Synthetic Model Spectra

https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stac2992

Lazarz et al. 2022 A&A, 668, A21

▶ SDSS-IV MaStar: Stellar Parameter Determination With Continuum-Supplemented Full-Spectrum Fitting

https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202243701

Lian et al. 2022 MNRAS, 513,3 **▶** The Milky Way tomography with APOGEE: density distribution and structure of mono-abundance populations

https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stac1151

Abdurro'uf et al. 2022 ApJS, 259, 35

▶ The Seventeenth Data Release of the Sloan Digital Sky Surveys

https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4365/ac4414

Hill et al. 2021 MNRAS, 509, 3

▶ SDSS-IV MaStar: Theoretical Atmospheric Parameters for the MaNGA Stellar Library

https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stab3263

Ahumada et al. 2019

▶ The Sixteenth Data Release of the Sloan Digital Sky Surveys

ApJS, 249, 3 https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4365/ab929e

Yan et al. 2019 ApJ, 883, 175

▶ SDSS-IV MaStar — A Large, Comprehensive, and Homogeneous Stellar Spectral Library

https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ab3ebc

Placco et al. 2015 ApJ, 812, 109 ▶ Hubble Space Telescope near-ultraviolet spectroscopy of bright CEMP-s stars

https://doi.org/10.1088/0004-637X/812/2/109

Work Experience

CURRENT POSITION

2023 - now Astronomical Data Scientist

Space Telescope Science Institute

Working at the Mikulski Archive for Space Telescopes (MAST) archiving astronomical data and sustaining database infrastructure in support of missions including SDSS, TESS, JWST, and HST.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2017 - 2023 Graduate Research Assistant

New Mexico State University

▶ Working with Dr. Jon Holtzman on the formation and evolution of the Milky Way through its stellar populations, APOGEE survey operations, and development of the MaNGA Stellar Library (MaStar).

2018 - 2021 APOGEE Data Reduction Specialist

Sloan Digital Sky Survey

Nightly data inspection and quality control for the APOGEE survey. Reduce data, update field completion status for survey planning and operation.

2014 - 2017 Undergraduate Research Assistant

University of Utah

Working with Dr. Inese Ivans in the Cosmic Origins research team. Involved in development and application of spectroscopic tools to study stellar populations and galactic evolution. Scholarships/Stipends: ACCESS; UROP, REU.

2016 - 2016 Space Astronomy Summer Program

Space Telescope Science Institute

Working with Dr. Rachel Osten to develop and maintain Space Telescope Live: an accessible social media account that acts as an effective live feed for what the Hubble Space Telescope is observing in real-time. https://spacetelescopelive.org/latesthttps://twitter.com/spacetelelive

2013 - 2014 ACCESS Program for Women in Science

University of Utah

Program designed to expose undergraduate women to professional laboratory environments from all fields of science. Investigated topics include Brownian motion, cosmic rays, cryptography, biological cloning, organic chemistry, protein denaturation, and topology.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

2022 - now	Milky Way as a Galaxy Working Group Co-Chair	Sloan Digital Sky Survey
2023	NASA FAIR Data Workshop Organizing Committee	NASA Science Mission Directorate
2019 - 2021	Inclusive Astronomy Meeting Coordinator	New Mexico State University
2019 - 2020	Astronomy Graduate Student Organization President	New Mexico State University

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2017 - 2019 Teaching Assistant

New Mexico State University

ASTR 110: Introduction to Astronomy. Responsible for teaching the interactive laboratory sessions and making myself available as tutor and resource for introductory-level astronomy. Instructors: Dr. Anatoly Klypin (Fall 2017, Spring 2019) and Dr. Jason Jackiewicz (Spring 2018, Fall 2018)

2020 - now

Undergraduate Student Mentoring

New Mexico State University

- ▶ FRIENDS Mentoring Program: Astronomy Department internal program that pairs up graduate students with undergraduates going for an Astronomy Minor, to provide mentorship, help with applications for graduate programs and summer internships, and encourage participation in department activities. I was a Mentor in the FRIENDS program from 2020-2022.
- **Research Group Mentoring:** Assisted in mentoring undergraduate students in our research group with Jon Holtzman, meeting weekly, helping with research, teaching PYTHON, and co-authoring papers.

2017 - now **C**

Outreach & Science Communication

New Mexico State University

- ▶ Volunteered at public outreach events representing NMSU operating telescopes, show-casing meteorites, and other hands-on activities. **Selected Events:** New Mexico Space Festival, El Paso Space Festival, NMSU Astronomy Telescope Open House, New Mexico Pride Festival, Eclipse Viewings, Astronomy on Tap.
- ▶ **Resource Development:** In 2019, involved in a small committee tasked with developing new outreach materials for the Astronomy Department. Gathering Supplies, writing instructions for volunteer training, 3D printing space-related models and telescope parts.
- **Letters to Pre-Scientist:** National pen-pal program pairing 5th to 10th grade students from low income communities with real scientists, designed to expose more students to STEM fields and demystify STEM careers. I participated during the 2020-2021 school year.

Invited Talks & Conferences

>>> Invited Tai	LKS	
3/03/2023	A Galactic Self-Portrait: 3D density map and integrated properties of the Milky Way	NMSU Thesis Defense
11/10/2022	A Galactic Self-Portrait: Chemical Cartography and Density Structure of the Milky Way Disk	University of Utah HEAP Seminar
DESCRIPTION CONFERENCE OFFICE OFF	CE PRESENTATIONS (ORAL)	
12/02/2022	A Galactic Self-Portrait: Chemical Cartography and Density Modeling of the Milky Way Disk	Linking the Galactic and Extragalactic, Wollongong, Australia
6/14/2022	3D density modeling of the Milky Way disk	240th AAS Meeting
4/16/2021	A Galactic Self-Portrait: 3D density map and integrated properties of the Milky Way	NMSU Thesis Proposal
1/12/2021	Data-driven parameter derivation for the MaStar library	237th AAS Meeting
6/23/2020	Data-driven parameter derivation for the MaStar library	SDSS Collaboration Meeting
03/02/2020	Data-driven parameter derivation for the MaStar library	SDSS-IV MaStar Busy Week
08/11/2016	Hubble Live: Developing an accessible livefeed for the Hubble Space Telescope	STScI Space Astronomy Summer Program Symposium
07/28/2015	The Milky Way's Neighbor: Chemical composition of ultra-faint dwarf galaxy Boötes I	Department of Physics Research Symposium
C		
SELECTED (Conference Presentations (Poster)	
11/28/2022	A Galactic Self-Portrait: Chemical Cartography and Density Modeling of the Milky Way Disk	Linking the Galactic and Extragalactic, Wollongong, Australia
06/16/2022	Mapping the Milky Way with the final data release of APOGEE	240th AAS Meeting
08/12/2021	3D density modeling of the Galactic Disk using APOGEE (Lightning Talk)	SDSS Collaboration Meeting
10/14/2019	Recent Initiatives to Promote Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion in the NMSU Astronomy Department	Inclusive Astronomy 2 Conference
04/01/2019	Integrated Spectrum of the Solar Neighborhood	MaNGA Collaboration Meeting
04/04/2017	Galactic evolution of phosphorus and sulfur using star clusters	Undergraduate Research Symposium
01/26/2016	Chemical composition of ultra-faint dwarf galaxy Boötes I	Research on Capitol Hill Event

FELLOWSHIPS AND AWARDS

2023 NMSU College of Arts & Sciences Outstanding Graduate Award

Nomination-based award for outstanding PhD graduants in the College of Arts & Sciences at New Mexico State University.

2022 Most Informative Poster Award

"Most Informative Poster" Award at the Linking the Galactic and Extragalactic, Wollongong, Australia. For poster "A Galactic Self-Portrait: Chemical Cartography and Density Modeling of the Milky Way Disk"

2022 NMSU Graduate Student Success Scholarship

Merit-based tuition fellowship awarded to graduate assistants who display excellence in forwarding the teaching or research mission of New Mexico State University.

NMSU College of Arts & Sciences Graduate Student Travel Grant

Fellowship provided to cover professional travel to conferences for graduate students from the College of Arts & Sciences at NMSU.

2021 Scott Murrell Endowed Memorial Scholarship

Awarded in recognition of professional development and research accomplishment as a graduate student in the Astronomy Department at NMSU.

2017 William Webber Voyager Graduate Fellowship

Awarded to support promising incoming graduate students and provide research funding during the first two years at NMSU.

2017 NMSU Graduate Tuition Fellowship

Awarded to cover full tuition for graduate students at NMSU.

2016 • University of Utah Outstanding Undergraduate Student Researcher

Awarded for exceptional undergraduate student research in the Honors College at University of Utah

2014 Walter W. Wada Endowed Scholarship in Physics & Astronomy

Awarded to Physics majors nominated by faculty for active participation in research and related activities on campus.

2013 **University of Utah Presidential Scholar**

Full tuition scholarship awarded to exceptionally promising incoming students.

REFERENCES

Dr. Jon Holtzman New Mexico State University - primary PhD advisor - holtz@nmsu.edu

Dr. Gail Zasowski University of Utah - MWAG / APOGEE collaborator - gail.zasowski@gmail.com

Dr. Renbin Yan
Chinese University of Hong Kong - MaStar Project Scientist - yanrenbin@gmail.com

Dr. Moire Prescott New Mexico State University - secondary PhD advisor - mkpresco@nmsu.edu